Josh Woodcock // Front-End Developer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w0 // j0w0.com // linkedin.com/in/j0w0

Front-End Developer experienced in building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications by utilizing appropriate technologies and applying best practices and industry standards.

Skills/Technologies: React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SCSS, Next.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, GraphQL, Vite, jQuery, Git, Jira, cloud-based deployment services, creating and consuming RESTful APIs, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress and Headless Content Management Systems. Code and demos are available on my <u>GitHub</u>.

Experience

Front-End Developer

Freelance | January 2023-Present | Austin, Texas

• Front-End focused web developer working with React and JavaScript. Open to new opportunities.

Full-Stack Developer

Hahn | May 2022-December 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Overhauled legacy Learning Management System by developing a new system with React and Wordpress, resulting in quicker and more intuitive content entry, member usability, and a decrease in loading times.
- Develop, implement, and maintain new features for client websites, apps, and content management systems.
- Tech stack used includes React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SCSS, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress.

Front-End Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021-May 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Developed front end of brand and artist web apps for streaming concerts, including real-time chat and donations.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Styled Components, Google Firebase.

Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy Urgent Care | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that helped win two stages of funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Twilio, Stripe, WooCommerce.

MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017–January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Architected/developed custom Wordpress theme and plugins allowing for easier management and sharing of content.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.
- Tech stack used includes HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ¡Query, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, Twilio, Stripe.

Education

Texas State University

General Assembly

BFA, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas

Software Engineering | Austin, Texas